People always ask me
what's so exciting
about riding a motorcycle.
It's noisy.
It's dangerous.
What does a street racer want?
What are we looking for?
What do we want?
Aren't we afraid of death?
Aren't we tired of making a scene?
For me, I would say…
SALAHUDDIN ROAD
No. We're not tired of it.
My first love is speed.
Once you twist the throttle
until your hands are numb,
once you see how
the world turns to a blur…
all of your problems
will go away.
If you're not happy, then start a game!
Tell your stupid boss, Boy,
don't send his goons
to bother me at night.
Cocky, are we? You're Azam, right?
If your bike is that great,
what are you waiting for?
Do I look scared?
Just you wait.
Wait?
You're the scaredy-cat, you goon!
Idiot.
Standing in the street? Are you blind?
Yes, I am. So what?
SULTAN ISMAIL PARK
Do you really live here?
I am blind. I can't see.
How do you know this is your flat?
What if I had taken you elsewhere?
What if I sell you? You wouldn't know.
That's a motorcycle lot, right?
There are flags up there.
I can see a bit in the day.
Harder at night.
Your loss.
You can't see my handsome face.
Hey.
I'm sorry that I nearly hit you earlier.
It's okay.
Thank you for bringing me home.
Hey!
You…
That was close.
Back from work?
Yes. At a hardware store near here.
But why are you following me?
Nothing. I just don't want you to fall.
I use these stairs every day.
A blind person
can work at a hardware shop?
What? Are we only qualified
to be a masseuse?
It's just a question.
Ratna? You're home late today.
Who is this?
A friend, Sis Mila.
He just had an accident.
Goodness. Wait there.
I'll get some medicine.
Come on in.
No, thanks. I have to go now.
Just come in.
You're not a murderer, are you?
No.
My name is Azam.
Ratna.
Ratna…
Don't move.
Your parents are not home?
My dad is in Johor Bahru.
My mum has passed.
Aren't you afraid of being alone?
There could be ghosts. Or Orang Minyak.
Okay. Done.
Can't you answer your phone?
The pipes are in. It'll be done tonight.
Seriously?
-Hurry!
-Wait there. I'll be there soon.
Ratna.
I have to go now.
Thank you.
For nursing me and all that.
Okay. Thank you.
Peace be upon you.
Azam!
What is it?
It's nothing.
-Zero-one-seven…
-Wait!
Two-seven-seven,
grandma falls from heaven.
Come on.
-No need then.
-Do you want it or not?
Of course I do.
Okay. Today will be the last
and final day
for the Red Leo exhaust sale.
Look closely. I will show it to you.
One more thing. If you buy it today,
you'll get a free sticker.
You won't get it tomorrow.
Okay. I have to go now.
If anything, DM me.
Straight up!
That's enough of that.
Hey.
You're just a coolie of the workshop.
Come and work on this bike.
Azam.
Boy's goons are angry.
What did you tell Kutu?
I saw the comments on my livestream.
Let them say whatever.
What are we waiting for?
Let's go.
-Are you ready?
-Show it.
Announcing the arrival of Your Majesty…
My God!
Azam.
Are you sure about racing with this?
It's too valuable.
If you sell it, you can get
around RM20,000 to RM30,000.
You know how bad
this illegal stuff is, right?
Anything happens, you'll end up dead.
Come on.
Just say you want to race.
This baldy!
Shut up.
Jimmy.
I will not die as long as
we haven't achieved our target.
How long will you use your mum's Kriss?
Doing deliveries all day
and the workshop at night.
Repairing bikes.
For how long?
Jimmy, this guy's sister's college fee
is about RM40,000. That's too much!
Didn't you tell me that one day
you'll have your own workshop?
How long do you want to work
as a mechanic here, Mat Jet?
The thing is, if we start a game,
we only need to win RM20,000
three to four times.
I'm sure all your problems
and Mat Jet's problems will be resolved.
Even mine too.
That's our target.
Trust me.
This bike…
will change our lives.
Trust me.
Mat Jet, help Jimmy.
CUP PRIX GEM
A HOPE FOR MALAYSIA
Along, what are you doing? Get up now.
Get up!
Get up. Sit over there.
Why are you eating like this?
Sit here.
What is this? You're making a mess.
I told you, tell me if you need to eat.
I will get it for you.
Angah.
Angah, don't you have any money coming in?
Anything?
What do you mean?
Lend me some, Angah.
Just a bit.
If you're planning to buy drugs,
you can ask me a thousand times,
or cry yourself a river,
you will still get none.
Angah. Angah.
Angah.
It's only because I feel sorry for you
that I promise you
we will leave this place.
Is Arash okay?
Who knows? I don't want to think about it.
It's tiring.
No need to think.
Let's just think about this.
Where did you get this?
My mum found it.
-You look the same.
-Haven't aged a bit.
Azam.
If you seriously
want to race with the bike,
how about you let me join you?
I mean, if we do it together,
the faster we will get to our target.
You're still jerky on the clutch.
I am not trying to criticize you.
You know you're not good at it.
You know how dangerous it is. Don't do it.
It's just that you're doing
everything on your own.
Remember what we used to say?
We will conquer KL together.
But that was when we'd race on bicycles.
Come on, man. See you tomorrow.
Ciao.
SORRY, I AM BLIND
RING THE BELL TO PAY
-How much?
-That's RM40.
Wait.
Received. RM40.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Hey!
-It's okay…
Relax. It's me. Azam.
What is that you're drawing?
What are you doing here?
Don't be mad.
Am I bothering you?
I'm here to invite you for lunch.
What time will you be off work?
In a moment.
What are you looking at?
You need a car for a date, right?
Come on. Don't be a brat.
Hey.
Hang on.
Send photo to Sis Milah.
Sis Milah, I'm going out with Azam.
I'll be home a bit late.
Sis Milah gets worried if I'm home late.
Okay.
This isn't the previous bike, right?
No.
Straighten your head for the helmet.
Get on.
The previous bike is cuter.
But this one is louder!
So, you love to do art?
And you? Street racing?
I can recognize it
from the sound of your bike.
Why?
Do you hate street racers?
Not at all.
But I always hear it on the news.
It's dangerous to ride at high speed.
I don't know.
You won't understand even if I tell you.
It's okay not to understand.
Just knowing is fine.
My brother was once a racer.
Both legally and illegally.
My parents died when I was a child.
So, my brother became my guardian.
But that was then.
After his accident,
he started using drugs.
He's different now.
But the thing is, I have to race.
That's the only way
for someone like me to make money.
You know, my late father
has a house in Perlis.
When I have enough money,
I want to repair the place.
I will take Arash there.
Away from KL.
Get on the bike. Wear your helmet.
Boy.
Kutu, was this the guy
who talked about me?
The very same.
Boy, do your parents allow you
to be out this late?
Do you think Boy is scared
of this new bike of yours?
He is. Not me.
I want to start a game.
Fifty.
Fifty thousand?
Do you think I'm stupid?
Just race with your family, Boy.
You're not like me. You have your dad.
I don't. Mine is dead.
You can ask for money from daddy.
You know why?
Because your dad is stupid.
Just like you!
Boy, you can't just ignore it.
What are you waiting for? Go after him!
Hey, Zahar. Use your bike, you idiot!
Who are those people?
What do they want?
It's nothing, Ratna. Just some idiots.
Don't worry, alright?
If anything happens,
I will protect you. Okay?
Hey, Jimmy. Why are you lying down?
Who's going to work on the bike?
Huh?
I went from Dengkil to Gombak,
and turned back to Cheras to do delivery.
Mum's Kriss is in dire condition.
Give me some space, man.
I am looking for a purple RXZ.
Plate number, KEU 51.
Azam has caused a problem.
This rascal is called Azam.
He has a workshop.
Find it, and I will give you a bonus.
How about that?
Call Azam.
What now?
Here.
Now it's better. Here.
It's okay. Keep it for now.
Here.
A whistle.
If someone is bothering you
or you fall down or something,
just blow the whistle,
and I will be there.
Yes, like that.
I can be a referee.
You can show the yellow card too.
Thank you, Azam.
I have to go now.
Be careful.
Azam.
This wasn't a date, right?
You need a car for a date, right?
Okay. Goodbye!
Goodbye.
-Mat Jet.
-Too deaf to hear the phone ring?
I was on the bike. Shut up.
-What's up?
-Come home now.
Your house is being surrounded.
Wait for me there.
Peace be upon you!
Azam? Azam!
Jet, if Azam is not here in 10 minutes,
just call the police.
Why would we call the police?
Let's just fight them!
That's stupid!
Boy pummeled a Cheras kid once.
He was in the ICU for a month!
So stupid!
Just eat your pumpkin seed.
This is ridiculous!
Kutu, are you waiting for revelation?
Aye, aye, Chief.
So many of you!
Jimmy! Mat Jet!
What's up? Is there an event?
Boy.
If you missed me,
no need to find me at home.
You do know, right?
I only need to snap my fingers,
and you will be crushed.
I know. But your mutts are awesome.
How much do you make?
Does it come with SOCSO?
Better than your goons.
No balls.
Next weekend.
RXZ Open. RM100,000.
Okay. I promise you I will be there.
Okay? You two, remember my face.
But let's sell your sister first.
Relax, Boy. This can be discussed.
Hey, you bum. Do you think I care?
You're just a hick.
People only respect you
because you are Arash's brother.
But what happened to him?
He's an addict, right?
Just a scum, right?
Come to the game,
or I will kill that addict.
What now, Azam?
What do you mean "what now"?
None of you helped when they pummeled me.
I think we should leave KL.
Where can we get RM100,000?
But what if I win?
If you win.
If you don't?
You'll be a slave.
I am confident I'll win.
I don't want you to regret it.
Jet.
Use the workshop's money.
Are you serious?
I don't mind,
but it still won't be enough.
I have my savings.
Put in your savings as well,
it'll be enough.
I don't have much, Azam.
Let alone Mat Jet.
The bike as well.
What say you?
DAD'S HOUSE REPAIR
ROOF RM7K, DOOR X FOUR RM2.5K,
WIRING RM5K
PLUMBING RM4K - FLOORING RM10K
ARASH'S HOSPITAL BILL RM20,000
Next weekend.
RXZ Open. RM100,000.
If you lose, you'll be a slave.
Where did you get the money?
Did you sell your trophy?
You sold it, didn't you? I'm asking you!
-Get up!
-My leg hurts. My leg hurts!
-You sold your trophy, didn't you?
-No…
How could you sell it?
Are you stupid?
Shut up, you scum!
You're the scum!
Do you think you're so great?
So great that you can teach me?
I took care of you.
You and I are no different.
What did you say?
Repeat that again, Along.
Repeat that. What did you say?
What's the difference?
Between you racing illegally
and me doing drugs?
Tell me.
That thing you do can kill you.
This thing I do can kill me.
Same difference, Angah.
I have to race.
I have to make money.
So that I can repair
Dad's house in the village!
Can't you think?
Your stupid friends
won't be able to find you anymore!
You will be healthy again.
Can you understand that?
Healthy?
Healthy, I see.
Did I say I want to be healthy?
Did I say that, Angah?
I just want my stuff.
This. I just want my stuff!
Do you even understand?
Drats.
Along.
I'm tired.
I am so tired of carrying
a burden like you.
From now on,
you're no longer my brother.
Angah.
Slumdogs like us?
We'll be a nuisance for life.
You remember that.
It's all spilled, Angah.
Jet.
If Azam loses, where will you go?
They said that tickets to Maldives
are cheap right now.
What will you do in Maldives?
Become a mechanic.
Idiot.
A mechanic?
-Hey, Azam.
-Azam…
I've been setting the bike up for a week.
It's in perfect condition.
Azam.
Go for a test ride
instead of meeting your girl.
The game is tonight.
I know. The bike is all set up right?
See you tonight.
Don't forget tonight!
I have a bad feeling about this.
So, the Maldives tickets are cheap?
Why?
I told you, you buffoon!
BLIND RATNA
Who are you?
Where is Ratna?
Azam, right?
Yes.
You took Ratna on a bike ride?
I don't mind.
But…
Can you help me?
Help you?
Please tell Ratna to come home.
But why?
Why aren't you living with her?
That night was
the biggest mistake of my life.
-Get my medicine.
-Mum?
Mum!
Mum.
Mum, wake up.
I made a mistake
by not looking after my wife and daughter.
Ratna wouldn't forgive me.
But maybe you can help me.
Ratna.
Ratna!
Sir, it's fine. I'll go see her.
-Ratna.
-Let me instead.
She's my daughter.
Sorry for having to say this.
If it were me,
and my dad left me, a blind person,
to live with a mum with heart disease,
and she passed away,
do you think…
I would forgive my dad?
Who are you?
Do you think I care
what a slumdog like you thinks?
Ratna.
Ratna, why didn't you answer my calls?
Listen up, everybody.
I am looking for a purple RXZ.
Plate number KEU 51.
The rascal is called Azam.
Sis Milah showed me the video.
Are you upset with me?
No.
Sis Milah is worried
that you'll drag me too.
Drag you to where?
It's okay. I will talk to Sis Milah.
Ratna.
Are you going fishing?
Ratna, are you buying a fish?
Or were you upset
that I spoke to your dad?
No.
I just like this place.
It's colourful.
Azam.
It must be strange, right?
I'm blind.
And yet I like to draw.
My mum always said that in life…
You will feel less burdened
once you find what you like.
But I'm blind, Azam.
How can I like something
when I can't see it?
But I see them, Azam.
After my mum died,
I promised myself
I wouldn't be sad anymore.
I want to live,
and I want to be happy.
That's why I decided to draw.
Drawing makes me feel…
alive.
But it's okay.
You might not understand.
It's okay not to understand.
Just knowing is fine.
Where is Azam?
Call him.
Come on!
Are you waiting for a feast?
Ratna.
I do feel sorry for your dad.
A bit guilty too.
You really don't want to forgive him?
In the past,
I loved playing at Dad's hardware store.
That's how I memorized
all the stuff there.
He wanted me to stay put,
so he taught me to draw.
I felt really happy
when Dad praised my drawing.
But he was never there for Mum.
From when she was healthy
to when she was ill.
Dad busied himself with work.
That's why I left.
And stayed in his old flat.
I don't know why,
but I can't stop thinking,
if Dad wasn't around,
maybe Mum and I…
would have been happier.
Ratna, do you know?
The first time I found out
that Arash used drugs,
I was enraged.
I mean, just imagine.
He's like a father to me.
But I still take care of him.
No matter what, he is still Arash.
My hero.
But men are like that.
We're a bit of a fool.
Especially with people we love.
Just relax, okay?
Excuse me. Sorry.
Can you check your phone?
MAT JET 17 CALLS
Thank you. Ratna, I have to go.
You know how to go home?
Okay.
-It's okay. I will look after her.
-Cool!
Are you going to race, Azam?
You still owe me a date.
Be careful.
Ratna, once I win,
I can take you on a date
all the way to London!
-Okay, thank you.
-Good luck.
I will book her a Grab car, okay?
How awful. Your buddy has left you two.
Do you think Azam is afraid of you, Boy?
What did you say?
You vermin.
You and your lollipop bike.
Who do you think you are?
At least that lollipop bike
was bought with my own cash.
You only have daddy's money.
You have a problem with me?
And what's up with you?
What's up?
RM100,000, right?
I'll wager RM70,000.
The rest of it on the bike.
Do you think your bike is RM30,000?
Okay, that's fine.
But poor you.
No money for your brother's drugs.
Get ready.
Guys!
Boy is your racer, right?
Your champion, right?
Tonight,
I will entertain you with one eye closed!
I will eat your sugar daddy!
Boy!
What are we waiting for? Let's start!
A hundred, Azam!
Keep the money safe, Jet.
See that?
Boy, what's your deal?
I'm sorry that you lost.
-Seriously?
-You handle it.
Boy, no need to worry.
Later, daddy will transfer some money.
You know what to do, right?
Did you see Boy's face earlier?
Like a sourpuss.
Okay. We have divided the money.
Everything's okay?
-It is.
-You bet…
Azam, if you have the time,
I think I want a new stock.
You should end it with your girl.
It's getting boring.
No, thanks.
I have something else tomorrow.
Okay. I have to go now.
Peace be upon you.
And you.
This guy is worrying me.
Where is he going with his money?
Massage.
Hurry up!
-Be careful, Jet!
-Be careful…
Azam, you do realize, right?
You have the money now.
You can start anew.
Jimmy, you know, earlier,
Boy's goons, both 125ZR riders,
tried to throw my game during the race.
Don't change the topic.
You're the one who said
that once you got the money,
you would leave with Arash.
You can take Arash
to a private clinic with that.
You're such a spoilsport.
Just tell me you want my bike.
You want to be a racer, right?
Azam.
Of course I want to be a racer, like you.
But I am not great at it.
Azam.
I have an idea.
Before you leave,
how about you train me first?
When did I say I'm leaving?
We'll see about that.
DAD'S HOUSE REPAIR
ROOF RM7K, DOOR X FOUR RM2.5K
WIRING RM5K
PLUMBING RM4K
FLOORING 10K
Ratna!
Ratna.
Wear something nice. Let's go.
Wow. You look pretty.
Here.
-Is this new?
-Yes.
That's why it smells nice. Unlike before.
You are so ungrateful.
-Do you want to try something new?
-What?
This!
Here.
One for me.
And one for you.
When the wind is blowing in your face,
just listen to the music.
And close your eyes.
Trust me.
All of your problems will be gone.
Really.
Your bangs will be ruined.
Let's wear the helmet.
Get your head straight.
Wow!
-Is that okay?
-Yes.
Okay.
Let's go.
Why do I have to close my eyes?
It's not like I can see.
That's true.
You're blind.
Let's go.
Azam.
Azam, answer the phone.
Mum, I have to go now.
Okay. Be careful.
Don't go too fast on that bike.
The maximum is only 200km per hour.
This boy!
-I'm going.
-Be careful.
Make supplication.
Jimmy, my boy.
Ma'am.
That's your son, right?
I have some issues with him.
What is wrong with you?
Aren't you afraid of God?
Jimmy.
Boy!
Boy, that's my mum! Boy!
Jimmy, sorry that I kicked your mum.
Boy.
Boy, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Boy. Please.
I will bow down to you.
Boy.
Send my regards to your best friend.
Look carefully.
Boy.
So, will you return to your hometown?
You have enough money
to repair the house, right?
It's not that much.
But I'm still unsure.
Why?
Do you still want to race?
Arash.
Arash can't be helped anymore.
I'm tired of him.
But I have you here.
If I blow this whistle,
you will come, right?
Azam.
Come closer.
What is it?
Why are you laughing?
Arash.
Arash, don't play around. Wake up.
Along.
Along, wake up.
Don't play with me.
Wake up, Along. Please.
Condolences, Azam.
Jet, what happened?
Boy sends his regards.
Azam.
The doctor said,
my arm may not return to how it was.
Why are you moving your stuff?
Azam, I think this is where
I stop being your mechanic.
I called you yesterday. You didn't answer.
Jet. Where is Jimmy?
Boy raided Jimmy's place.
His bike was burned down.
His mum has gone back to the village.
He was badly beaten.
Boy?
Why?
Where are you going?
You want to seek revenge?
You want to be a cripple too? Like Arash?
Jet.
I think…
you should just go stay with your girl.
You love to ruin people's lives, right?
Azam.
Why are you quiet?
You don't want to be friends anymore?
No.
It's just that Arash…
Arash is dead.
Ratna, you don't have to come
find me anymore.
You don't even need to call me.
A street racer like me
will just make life harder for you.
Really?
That's what you think.
When did you ever make life hard for me?
Just listen to me, Ratna.
You're still young.
And you're pretty.
Sooner or later, you will forget me.
I will never forget.
Remember this, Ratna.
I will forget you.
What are you doing here?
You have no right to live.
Jimmy, relax.
I had to save face.
It was my men who wanted to beat you up.
What can I do?
Jimmy, relax.
Okay. How much do you want?
I will pay you.
Send my regards to your best friend.
Watch closely.
Ratna.
I know you hate me.
But can you wait and hear me out first?
Peace be upon you.
And you. Come on in.
Ratna.
Are you well?
Ratna, my name is Sarah.
Your artworks are beautiful.
I know a gallery owner.
They have a lot of artworks
made by people like you.
And they have an art school there.
You can learn how to draw,
and then you can sell all your artwork.
Enough is enough, Ratna.
Don't you care for me?
Hey!
Isn't this Boy's bike?
Tell me. This is Boy's, right?
What did you do to him?
Don't make me go to the police!
Friends!
Whichever one of you
can break this guy's face,
I will reward him RM5,000!
Yes!
Will you accept?
Hey, seriously?
We're friends!
Hey, we're all friends.
Have you guys forgotten that?
Thank you.
Azam!
What are you doing here?
Tomorrow morning,
Dad wants me to go with him.
That's good then.
But I don't want to go.
Don't do anything foolish.
What's the matter with you?
You were fine before.
Azam.
You know what I want to say, right?
-Azam, I…
-Ratna, let's not talk about this.
Stay inside, okay?
Where were you, Jimmy?
Well…
You were picking up a disabled chick?
Don't you have sympathy for your mum?
What is it to you?
Mat Jet and I were slaving away
in this place, and you never cared.
Things happen, Jimmy.
What do you want me to do?
You stole Boy's bike.
You hung out with the scums.
-What are you trying to do?
-Scums?
They may be scums, but they respect me.
What are you trying to prove?
-That you're powerful?
-I am.
Tonight. Same street.
I don't want to race with you!
You might have looked down on me.
If you don't want to race with me,
I will make her go mute.
Will you accept?
Hey!
Touch her, and I will smash your face.
You want a race?
If you lose, go back to your mum.
And if you lose?
Burn your bike and kiss my feet.
Okay?
If that will satisfy you…
Okay.
You see what my life is like, right?
Just go home.
Leave.
What's the matter, Ratna?
Ratna.
If this is about the stupid guy,
just forget him.
-Ratna--
-Shut up.
When can I join the art school?
Whenever you want.
As soon as possible.
Do you remember?
We would race after school.
Sometimes you win.
Sometimes I do.
We don't have to do this stupid race.
Why?
Lost your crush?
Today's game is a "Macha Original".
Jimmy?
Azam.
Jimmy, are you okay?
Jimmy!
Jimmy?
-My Car.
-Hold on, Jimmy.
Think of Allah. I told you, Jimmy.
Why must you do this stupid thing?
I wanted to be like you.
There is no need for it, Jimmy.
Call an ambulance!
What ambulance? Call the police!
Your friend should die!
I'm sorry, Azam.
I should be the one saying sorry.
I have done you a lot of wrong.
Jimmy.
You don't need to speak.
Just be quiet, Jimmy.
Just leave, Azam.
I will not leave, Jimmy.
-I will not leave.
-Just leave!
Hey!
Hey, where are you going?
Call the police.
Hurry and call the police.
Go!
Call the police now!
Jimmy?
Leave, Azam!
Hello, Sir.
A street racer got into an accident.
-Hey!
-Come back!
Hey!
Ratna.
You will not be alone anymore, okay?
Azam.
Azam?
Ratna.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean what I said to you before.
You were lying, right?
You won't leave me, right?
I was lying.
I knew it.
You were also lying
about returning to your hometown.
You were lying, right?
Azam?
But why, Azam?
-Why did you want to leave me so much?
-Ratna…
If I…
If a street racer like me…
a scum like me…
were to be with you,
your life would be stuck.
What are you talking about, Azam?
Ratna, just go.
Just go.
Don't stop drawing.
Listen to me.
Forget about me.
Just forget me.
I will never forget you, Azam.
WELCOME TO PERLIS
You want to sell the bike?
Take good care of it, okay?
Thank you.
Take care of this place properly, Jet.
Pursue your dream.
MAT JET MOTORSPORT
OPENING SOON
This is our gallery.
We display artwork
from special people like you.
We have framed all of your artwork here.
You're so talented.
But why is this frame empty?
Because the art is not with me.
What is it called?
"The Night's Angel."
A NAZIFDIN NASRUDIN FILM
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION
ANY SIMILARITY TO ORGANIZATIONS OR PEOPLE
IS PURELY COINCIDENTAL